hello hey you know my name's ed Byrnes
你好，嘿，你知道我叫埃德·伯恩斯
new humor okay there you go
新幽默好吧，你去
I'm very happy to be here speaking today
我很高兴今天在这里讲话
about JSF 2.3 so let's get right into it
关于JSF 2.3，让我们开始吧
this safe harbor statement is standard
此安全港声明是标准的
but everything I'm talking to you about
但是我在跟你谈论的一切
has already been done so you can count
已经完成，所以你可以数
on it okay so this talk assumes basic
就可以了，所以这个演讲假设基本
familiarity with JSF and JSF has lots of
对JSF和JSF的熟悉程度很多
flashy components and wonderful ways to
浮华的组件和美妙的方法
work with it there are other resources
使用它还有其他资源
to visit for that perspective on JSF
访问有关JSF的观点
this talk is more a little has a little
这个话题多一点
historical content in the front followed
前面的历史内容紧随其后
by some opinion on JSF and then the
对JSF的一些看法，然后
heart of the talk is the new feature
谈话的重点是新功能
review I'll be doing that entirely in
评论，我将完全在
NetBeans for the most part I'm just kind
在大多数情况下，NetBeans我都很友善
of open going in through the code and
通过代码打开和
then give you some words about opening
然后给你一些关于开放的话
up Java EE and the perspective on JSF
Java EE和JSF的观点
and I intend to leave five to ten
我打算离开五到十
minutes time for QA I even with our
分钟的质量检查时间，即使我们
short 45 minute session duration I think
我认为会议时长只有45分钟
we can do that and I kind of want to
我们可以做到，我有点想
keep it a little more interactive if
保持互动性
possible I know they're recording this
可能我知道他们正在录制这个
session and so whenever someone asks a
会议，所以每当有人问一个
question I'll be sure to answer repeat
问题，我一定会回答重复
the question so if you have a question
这个问题，所以如果你有一个问题
that you'd like to see address please
您想看到的地址
raise your hand even in the middle of
即使在中间也举手
the session so JSDF has been around for
会议，因此JSDF一直在
a long time this is 16 years of JSF it
很长时间，这是JSF的16年了
was announced that the Java 1 keynote in
宣布Java 1主题演讲
2001 does anyone remember seeing this
2001年有人记得这个吗
slide when it was first put up right on
首次安装时滑动
alright so the basic idea is still the
好吧，所以基本思想仍然是
same you know it's the simple Java
同样，您知道这就是简单的Java
server-side web framework thing and why
服务器端Web框架的内容以及原因
you know how can that possibly be still
你知道怎么可能仍然
relevant that's such a long time ago
如此久远的相关性
well abstractions and JSF at its heart
很好的抽象和JSF的核心
as any specification is really it is an
因为任何规范实际上都是
abstraction and it is an abstraction
抽象，它是一种抽象
that lets you build web apps that are
使您可以构建
quick to build maintainable localizable
快速构建可维护的本地化
it'll secure device-independent
它将确保与设备无关的安全
good-looking and are fun to use so while
漂亮，使用起来很有趣
preparing this session I did a little
准备本次会议我做了一点
research on stackoverflow here a number
关于stackoverflow的研究这里有很多
of stack overflow hits compared to some
相比某些堆栈溢出命中
other popular ones as of yesterday and
截至昨天的其他热门
JSF has the most that's some kind of
JSF的优势在于
metric I was talking to someone who is a
指标，我正在与某人交谈
PHP developer at the party one party
PHP开发人员参加聚会
last night did anyone go to that zero
昨晚有人去那个零
turnaround party one yeah okay
周转党一，是的，好的
have a good time all right thanks to
祝你玩得开心
those folks who are throwing that
那些扔那个的人
talking to a PHP developer and they said
与PHP开发人员交谈，他们说
yeah man the Stack Overflow thing is a
是的，Stack Overflow是一个
great measure of security because I have
很好的安全措施，因为我有
a sense
某种意义上
Akito have a sense that uh if any
秋藤有一种感觉，如果有的话
question I have there's gonna be an
问题，我会有一个
answer for it so now the perspective to
为此，现在来看
give you some perspective with this
给你一些观点
graph if you add PHP into it
图，如果您将PHP添加到其中
all of the others turn into noise so
所有其他都变成噪音，所以
that's just the thing I don't know I
那只是我不知道的事情
haven't I'm not a PHP user so I haven't
我不是PHP用户，所以我没有
really tried to do it but that's an
真的尝试这样做，但这是一个
awful lot of Stack Overflow
很多堆栈溢出
so JSF how can it still be relevant
所以JSF怎么仍然有意义
right
对
JSF has a long history incorporating
JSF具有悠久的历史
proven ideas from the community living
来自社区生活的可靠想法
communities indoor so it's not a dead
室内社区，所以它不是死人
thing it's an alive thing and it's an
这是一个活着的东西，这是一个
alive thing because of all the people
所有人都活着的东西
that I've come to know and work with
我已经认识并与之合作
over the years that are contributing and
这些年来，
still vibrant and active in this
仍然充满活力和活跃
community I've had the great great honor
社区，我感到非常荣幸
of working with some excellent engineers
与一些优秀的工程师一起工作
over the years inside and outside of the
多年来的内外
company that was sponsoring the
赞助的公司
development first Sun then Oracle and
首先开发Sun，然后是Oracle，
I've been always very blessed to be able
我一直很幸运能够
to take those ideas and bring them in
接受这些想法并将其引入
facelets Ajax website get pushed list
facelets Ajax网站获得推送列表
goes on and on of ideas that will you
不断地提出您的想法
know came in from the community and are
知道来自社区，
now in the core Java platform this is
现在在核心Java平台中
just a personal note this is 15 years
只是一个私人笔记，这是15年
six month and two days
六个月零两天
from when I gave my first ever JSF talk
从我第一次有JSF演讲开始
so I consider that a very great honor to
所以我觉得很荣幸
have such a long run and you know have
有这么长的时间，你知道有
some other stuff to talk about as you
和您讨论其他一些事情
saw yesterday oh I'm I'm in the
昨天见过哦，我在
background probably yeah that's what JSF
背景可能是的，这就是JSF
is right kind of in the background
在后台是正确的
another reason living communities indoor
室内居住社区的另一个原因
is there are two independent open-source
是否有两个独立的开源
implementations Arco Mahara the
实施Arco Mahara
reference implementation which is
参考实现
commonly seen in all these app servers
在所有这些应用程序服务器中常见
and Apache my phases which is seen this
和Apache我的阶段，这是看到的
is an incomplete list and all these app
是不完整的列表，所有这些应用
servers JBoss wildfly is done a great
服务器JBoss wildfly做得很棒
job you can see it's in both lists of
您可以在以下两个列表中看到它
making it easy to swap in between the
方便地在
different implementations so when I look
不同的实现，所以当我看
at JCP standards that have been done
按照已经完成的JCP标准
over the years I think JSF is the one
多年来，我认为JSF就是其中之一
that's most directly and provably
那是最直接和可证明的
delivered on the promise of having
兑现承诺
multiple separate implementations that
多个单独的实现
are swapping it I mean JSON you can do
交换它，我的意思是您可以执行JSON
that too but there's so much people so
那也有很多人
many people out there that are using a
许多人在那里使用
completely different idea in the form of
形式完全不同的想法
jackson that you have to rewrite the
杰克逊，你必须重写
code whereas with JSF you actually have
代码，而实际上使用JSF
some reasonable claim to deliver on the
一些合理的要求实现
value proposition of vendor independence
供应商独立性的价值主张
based on specifications so while
根据规格，所以虽然
preparing for this talk I had a
为这次演讲做准备，我有一个
conversation with my old friend and
与我的老朋友交谈，以及
frien faceless founder chuck I seviche
匿名的创始人查克·斯维奇
and I wanted to ask him since he was
我想问他，因为他是
most up-to-date on this how are people
关于这方面的最新信息
using JSF in contemporary context and
在当代环境中使用JSF
you know trying anyone here using
你知道在这里尝试任何人
primefaces a JSF component library okay
primefaces一个JSF组件库可以
a lot of folks
很多人
he says JSF is still being used lots of
他说JSF仍然被大量使用
back office applications government
后台应用程序政府
agencies banks that like to keep their
愿意保留他们的代理银行
business logic on the server side where
服务器端的业务逻辑在哪里
they have probably pretty conservative
他们可能很保守
requirements about data security and
有关数据安全性和
pushing business logic to the client
向客户推送业务逻辑
side another key use case which was JSF
另一个关键用例是JSF
was designed to appeal to this from the
旨在从
very beginning
一开始
and this was a style of application
这是一种应用风格
development that has since become less I
从那以后发展变得越来越少
don't know widespread for public facing
不知道面向公众的广泛传播
apps but for most apps that have a
应用，但对于大多数具有
captive audience where you this is the
俘虏的观众，你在哪里
thing you have to use whether it's just
你必须使用的东西是否只是
to do your job or it's what's your
做你的工作，或者这就是你的工作
agency that is using its lots of screens
使用大量屏幕的代理商
right so any app that's based from sort
正确，因此任何基于排序的应用
of screen based where the screens are
基于屏幕的位置
authored by many different people or
由许多不同的人创作或
teams they probably share a common
他们可能共享一个共同的团队
template it's good for that it is good
模板对它有好处，也有好处
enough many people already know how to
已经有足够多的人知道如何
use it it's kind of king of good enough
用它是足够好的国王
in some sense and it's also knows known
在某种意义上，它也知道
quantity it's easy to find people to be
数量很容易找到人
productive with it so does anyone else
富有成效，其他人也一样
have any perspectives they wanted to
有他们想要的观点
share on why they're still using it even
分享为什么他们仍在使用它
though it's very old and there's a lot
虽然很老而且有很多
of other choices yeah right
还有其他选择，对吧
you can't find people who want to do
你找不到想做的人
angular or JSF oh okay
角或JSF哦，好
so you're saying that you're saying a
所以你说的是
contrary is assertion is that it's a
相反，断言是
contrary point to find people who are
相反地​​找到谁是
productive to use data okay okay no it's
高效地使用数据好吧好吧不是
that's great data that's contrary to
那是大数据，与
what jatai soul told me maybe it's a
贾泰灵魂告诉我的也许是
market specific thing it could be that
市场特定的东西可能是
you know in Western Europe part where he
你知道在西欧他在那里
is it's more common I don't know any
这是更常见的我不知道吗
other perspectives
其他观点
[Music]
[音乐]
right
对
yeah it's your mouth very and so the
是的，这是你的嘴，所以
Jawas point was people pick up JSF
贾瓦斯（Jawas）的观点是人们接JSF
during school and then they come into
在学校期间，然后他们进入
the workplace and it's a different
工作场所，这是不同的
environment so anyhow there's some
环境，所以总有一些
opinion and we can talk more about that
意见，我们可以进一步讨论
later I'm going into the exhibition area
等一下我去展览区
if you want to bend my ear about this or
如果您想为此弯曲我的耳朵或
any other topic let's do the new feature
任何其他主题，让我们来做新功能
review before I do that though I want to
在我这样做之前先回顾一下，尽管我想
point out that we have moved everything
指出我们已经搬走了一切
about Java EE on to github and I have a
关于Java EE到github上，我有一个
separate section of the talk while I
在我讲话的另一部分
mean giving you my perspective on the
就是说给我我的观点
move to eclipse foundation the Java EE
成为Eclipse基础的Java EE
main landing page is Java EE to github
主登陆页面是Java EE到github
data and the samples that I'll be
数据和我将要使用的样本
showing for this and every other feature
显示此功能和所有其他功能
that's new and Java EE 8 is available at
这是新功能，Java EE 8在以下位置可用
that URL there so let's take a look at
那里的URL，所以让我们看一下
the new feature of you there are more
您的新功能还有更多
new features in JSF 2.3 than this but
JSF 2.3中的新功能
they all have the same kind of
他们都有相同的
characteristic of being you know little
你很少了解的特征
incremental feature ads right so you can
正确投放增量功能广告，这样您就可以
think about what they mentioned at the
想想他们在
keynote on Monday of Java itself the
Java本身周一的主题演讲
core java SE moving to an incremental
核心Java SE移至增量
release schedule we already kind of have
我们已经有的发布时间表
that for this but not the time frame
为此，但不是时间范围
right so we'll see if in the move to
对，所以我们将看看是否
eclipse they can get releases out more
日食他们可以释放更多
frequently I believe they will be able
我经常相信他们将能够
to use of servlet for Oh server push the
使用servlet进行哦服务器推送
good news on that is that mostly comes
好消息是，大多数情况下
for free
免费
in fact entirely comes for free if
实际上，如果
you're using straight-up JSF WebSocket
您正在使用直接的JSF WebSocket
push Ajax method invocation multi field
推送Ajax方法调用多字段
validation which is a really long
验证时间很长
sought-after feature
抢手功能
and tighter CDI integration and then if
和更紧密的CDI集成，然后
I get through all those I'll show you
我会告诉我所有的一切
know we can open the list up and if
知道我们可以打开列表，如果
anyone has any other features they want
任何人都有他们想要的其他功能
to explore it we can look at that start
探索它，我们可以看看那开始
out with server push so while I was
用服务器推送出去，所以当我
preparing for the talk I looked into
为我调查的演讲做准备
when it was added to put this finally in
当它被添加到最后
the spec for the implementation rather
实施规范
and came across the commit I made for it
并遇到了我为此所做的承诺
and I just thought it was kind of funny
我只是觉得这很有趣
here this will probably be the last
这可能是最后一个
commit to JSF on Java denied get before
在Java上提交到JSF被拒绝
moving to get up so I did the same it
移动起来，所以我做了同样的事情
also be the last JIRA filed before moved
也是移动之前最后提交的JIRA
to github issue tracker many thanks to
到github问题跟踪器，非常感谢
Jeff for all the great hosting over the
Jeff为所有出色的托管服务
years so we had when java.net first came
年，所以我们第一次来到java.net
out you know we had this on its own
你知道我们自己有这个
issue tracker thing and then they got a
问题跟踪器，然后他们得到了
license with Atlassian JIRA and that
Atlassian JIRA的许可证，以及
like totally changed our world and in
就像彻底改变了我们的世界
fact the development of JSF was very
事实上，JSF的发展非常
heavily improved by having a high
高
quality issue tracker like that we did a
像这样的质量问题跟踪器
lot of stuff with the community to take
很多东西带给社区
feedback in the issue tracker and we
问题跟踪器中的反馈，我们
entirely relied on JIRA during the spec
在规范期间完全依赖JIRA
development process to track which
开发过程跟踪
issues we were implementing and
我们正在实施的问题
everything so we got a lot done with it
一切，所以我们做了很多事情
and I did want to give a quick point to
我确实想简单指出
this blog post I made at the end of the
我在末尾发表的这篇博客文章
java.net era so long and thanks for all
java.net时代这么久，感谢所有人
the commits so this was important to me
提交，所以这对我很重要
because there was many people who worked
因为有很多人在工作
on java.net over the years and many
多年来，在java.net上
people who made the migration to github
迁移到github的人
a success thank you for that ok
成功谢谢你的确定
let's look at the code then so the first
让我们看一下代码，然后第一个
thing I wanted to just do is start with
我想做的就是从
a little demo and if you've seen my
一个小样，如果你看过我的
servlet talk kind of seeing something
servlet说话有点看东西
similar so in the GlassFish samples in
在GlassFish样本中也是如此
the servlet area they have a super super
servlet区域，他们有一个超级超级
simple server push wire that shows how
简单的服务器推线，显示了如何
to use server push outside of JSF and
在JSF之外使用服务器推送
the great thing about these samples is
这些样品的优点在于
that they're really you know showing
他们真的是你知道显示
bare bones right you don't have anything
裸露的骨头，你什么都没有
else in here
其他在这里
so this is a simple servlet and in the
所以这是一个简单的servlet，
do get method we take the request we ask
得到方法，我们接受我们提出的要求
it for the new push builder we add a CSS
对于新的推送构建器，我们添加了CSS
file and then we tell the push builder
文件，然后我们告诉推送生成器
to send the push and then we write out
发送推送，然后我们写出
the HTML that happens to reference that
恰好引用该HTML的HTML
CSS file and if we look in the webpages
CSS文件，如果我们查看网页
of course we'll see there's our CSS file
当然，我们会看到我们的CSS文件
the way this looks in the browser is
它在浏览器中的外观是
let's reload this and let's look at the
让我们重新加载它，让我们看看
chrome net internals and look at HTTP -
chrome net内部，看看HTTP-
and you can see if we select this you'll
您可以看到我们是否选择了此选项
see there is the server push let's see
看到有服务器推送，让我们看看
is it a push promise yeah there's the
这是一个推销承诺吗，是的
push promise this is the HTTP - pseudo
推送承诺，这是HTTP-伪
headers and the path of the CSS there so
标头和CSS的路径在那里
that's really simple and easy to
那真的很容易
understand
了解
on the jsf side because all of the
在jsf方面，因为所有
resources that JSF has associated with
JSF与之关联的资源
the pages it knows about in advance we
我们事先知道的页面
were able to modify the specification
能够修改规范
which I can show you right here this is
我可以在这里告诉你这是
a little actual text and the JSF 2.3
一点实际的文字和JSF 2.3
spec does anyone actually ever looked at
规范实际上没有人看过
any of the JSF or any other Java EE
任何JSF或任何其他Java EE
specs over the years well that's great
多年来的规格很好
do you think it's useful to have those
你认为有那些有用吗
okay because that's another aspect for
好的，因为那是另一个方面
the Eclipse thing is that every other
Eclipse的事情是
open-source project I can think of
我能想到的开源项目
doesn't bother with having a
不用理会
specification
规格
and a test suite I mean they probably
和测试套件，我的意思是他们可能
have test-driven development so they
有测试驱动的开发，所以他们
probably have a test suite so the thing
可能有一个测试套件，所以这件事
they really don't have is a spec thing
他们真的没有是规范的东西
so it'll be interesting to see how that
因此，看看如何
evolves because it's it has to be done
进化，因为它是必须要做的
in a lightweight fashion I think this is
以轻巧的方式，我认为这是
one of the things that the CDI folks
CDI员工之一
have done really well I mean ideally the
真的做得很好，我的意思是
spec should be able to be generated from
规范应该能够从
the code in the same way that Javadoc is
代码与Javadoc相同
and they've done that pretty well
他们做得很好
they've approximated that gotten pretty
他们估计这变得很漂亮
close to it with the combination of Java
与Java的组合接近它
doc and asciidoc in CDI so I hope that
CDI中的doc和asciidoc，所以我希望
they're able to pull that off
他们能够做到这一点
no exactly of course not everything
当然不是全部
that's that's why they fall back to
这就是为什么他们回落到
asciidoc so it's not a perfect solution
asciidoc，所以这不是一个完美的解决方案
and so the solution we've derived that
因此我们得出的解决方案是
over the years with JSF is you know do
多年来与JSF在一起，你知道吗
as much as possible in the generated
尽可能在生成的
documentation but when you need a
文档，但是当您需要
explanatory bit of text that spans a lot
跨度很大的文字说明
of different parts of the code that's
代码的不同部分
what the core specification is for so
核心规范是为了什么
this bit says here basically if you're
如果您是
running on server for use server push
在服务器上运行以使用服务器推送
and we wanted to keep it very high-level
我们希望将其保持在较高水平
specification so as long as it you know
规格，只要你知道
adhered to the HTTP requirements all of
遵守所有HTTP要求
the pushes must be started before any of
必须先开始推送
the HTML response is rendered to the
HTML响应将呈现给
client and there's a couple other
客户，还有另外两个
requirements in terms of the method that
在方法方面的要求
we knew we're going to be correct which
我们知道我们将是正确的
is it has to be safe and cashable so we
它必须安全且可兑现，所以我们
knew for all of the JSF resources that
对于所有JSF资源都知道
would fall under that umbrella so we in
会落在那把伞下，所以我们
our implementation we just chose to
我们只是选择执行
modify the external context class and
修改外部上下文类并
when it does it's in code action url'
当它在代码操作URL中时
which will be done for every resource
将为每种资源完成
that's going to be rendered we end up
这将被渲染，我们最终
end up calling this method here let's
最终在这里调用此方法
see
看到
to search this way necessary yeah push
搜索这种方式是必需的
if possible unnecessary so we do a
如果可能的话，那么我们做一个
little check to see if push is supported
很少检查是否支持推送
because we need to you know JSF still
因为我们需要您仍然知道JSF
even though it's a part of Java EE eight
即使它是Java EE八的一部分
it's possible to run it on older things
可以在较旧的东西上运行它
that might not have those classes
可能没有那些课程
although that's not a feature that we're
虽然这不是我们的功能
really supporting anymore we're saying
真的支持了，我们是说
you have to run it on Java on Java EE
您必须在Java EE的Java上运行它
eight container so we checked the
八个容器，所以我们检查了
attribute there if it's supported or not
是否支持该属性
we also don't want to push the do issue
我们也不想推办问题
another push we've already pushed this
另一个推动，我们已经推动了
URL because with JSF you might have lots
URL，因为使用JSF可能会有很多
of different pages and some of them
不同的页面，其中一些
might reference the same resources so
可能会引用相同的资源，因此
you keep track of that and we use
您跟踪它，我们使用
compute of absent to check that and then
计算缺席检查，然后
we add the resource URLs that's and here
我们在此处添加资源URL
we actually do the push so this is the
我们实际上做了推，所以这是
same code that you saw in the simple
您在简单的代码中看到的相同代码
example but it is built into the core
例子，但是它是内置的
JSF implementation and we also know that
JSF的实现，我们也知道
there's no if modified since header so
自从头以来没有修改过
if there's no if modified since header
如果自标头起没有修改
then we are safe to push there is a
那么我们可以安全地推动
modified since header then we know that
从头开始修改，那么我们知道
it's in the browser's cache and we're
它在浏览器的缓存中，我们
not going to push it so if we look at
不会推它，所以如果我们看一下
the more complex example of the
更复杂的例子
primefaces showcase which you've
您已经拥有的primefaces展示柜
probably seen you know it has a number
可能看到你知道它有一个数字
of images and resources here and if we
这里的图像和资源，如果我们
go back to the chrome net inspector you
回到您的铬网检查器
can see there's a few more push promises
可以看到还有更多的推送承诺
that are coming there usually I see it
我通常会看到那里
like a hundred and forty four so let me
像一百四十四点，让我
reload this shift reload
重新加载此班次重新加载
yeah there you go
是的，你去了
though there's just more of the same
虽然有更多相同的地方
push promises okay does anyone have any
推诺，好吧，有人有吗
questions about the server push okay it
关于服务器的问题推吧
is something that while I said it's
是我刚才说的
really easy it does like this is the
真的很容易，就像这样
general http/2 concerned it really HCB
一般的http / 2关注它真的HCB
to turns on its head the way you do a
以你做事的方式打开它的头
lot of the optimizations that you had to
您必须进行的许多优化
do in your websites before
之前在您的网站上做过
for example image sharding and I'm sorry
例如图像分片，对不起
domain sharding and image sprites are
域分片和图像精灵是
too technical techniques that people
人们太技术性的技巧
used to optimize performance prior to HC
在HC之前用于优化性能
b2 and those techniques don't they
b2和那些技术不是
actually make performance worse with
实际上使性能变差
HTTP 2 so you know you research it
HTTP 2，所以您知道您正在研究它
carefully before you do considered
在考虑之前要仔细
moving all everything over to http - yes
将所有内容移至http-是
F itself had never done any domain
F本身从未做过任何领域
sharding or image spriting for you so
分片或图像拼写为您
nothing will be done in that regard you
在这方面，你将一事无成
know did you have a question or
知道你有问题吗
observation
观察
good question great question question
好问题好问题
was is there way to turn it off right
有办法将其关闭吗
and so when we did this in the spec we
因此，当我们在规范中执行此操作时，
just wanted to keep it a super course so
只是想保持它超级课程，所以
currently no that is something that
目前不，那是
would have to be added you would imagine
您将不得不添加
you can easily imagine some way where
您可以轻松想像一下
you can define parts of your page or
您可以定义页面的一部分或
some kind of resource pattern that would
某种资源模式
match or even actually maybe in the
匹配，甚至实际上可能在
resource library itself would have some
资源库本身会有一些
way of indicating push these resources
指示推送这些资源的方式
or not so but the answer is everything
还是不是，但答案是一切
is pushed if you have HCB to on the
如果您要使用HCB，则将其推送
browser can turn it off of course and I
浏览器当然可以将其关闭，而我
think you know I showed you the code
想你知道我给你看了代码
there's what you probably could do is
你可能可以做的是
have a filter in there that takes that
那里有一个过滤器
attribute and puts it and then disables
属性并将其放置，然后禁用
it that way so there's a way to work
这样，就有一种工作方式
around everything okay all right let's
一切都好吧，让我们
go now from the web server push to
现在从网络服务器推送到
website and push now these are different
网站和现在推送这些是不同的
kinds of pushes the WebSocket push is
各种推送WebSocket推送是
much more intentional and application
更多的有意和应用
level so we have an example in the Java
级别，因此我们在Java中有一个示例
EE samples let me make sure I close the
EE样本让我确保我关闭了
other stuff I don't need any more we are
我不需要的其他东西
and I also want to give a big big big
而且我也想给一个很大的很大
shout out and thank you to my co speckly
大声喊着，谢谢你我的合作
and colleague manfred green he was my
和同事曼弗雷德·格林，他是我的
full partner in Khost but lead on this
霍斯特（Khost）的正式合伙人，但在此方面处于领先地位
and it's fortunate he wasn't able to be
幸运的是他没能力成为
here to present with me and also he took
在这里和我一起礼物
the time to put together the sample
整理样品的时间
editions here so this is a single war
版本在这里，所以这是一次战争
that you can deploy that has a nice
您可以部署的一个很好的
[Music]
[音乐]
title page with all of the samples and a
标题页以及所有示例和
typical simple style we have them all
典型的简单风格，我们都拥有
listed out for you there so let's look
在那里为您列出了，让我们来看一下
at the websocket sample and if you just
在websocket示例中，如果您只是
click send a message you go back to the
单击发送消息，您将返回到
previous window and there's a message
前一个窗口，有一条消息
that it's been pushed so let's look at
它已经被推动了，让我们来看一下
the code
编码
websocket
网络套接字
okay so here you have a Facebook page
好的，所以在这里您有一个Facebook页面
supposed to make this big
应该做的这么大
also you'll see that we've got the ugly
你也会看到我们很丑
red line of the version of NetBeans I
NetBeans I版本的红线
have here doesn't have the Java EE 8
这里没有Java EE 8
stuff in it and I'm sorry I don't have
里面的东西，对不起，我没有
an answer on when that will be available
关于何时可用的答案
this has been a bit of a different thing
这有点不同
and I haven't heard much about what's
而且我还没听说什么
going on with NetBeans regarding Java
关于Java的NetBeans的发展
et8 so I can't answer that so all of the
et8，所以我无法回答所有问题
great documentation not a completion you
出色的文档不是您的完成
expect is not quite working here so you
期望在这里工作不大，所以你
have let me actually pull up the Java
让我实际使用Java
doc to locally no I don't have it handy
doc到本地，否，我没有用
okay we'll just have to go with the code
好吧，我们只需要处理代码
so you create a channel that is
因此您创建了一个
basically a name and you have to use
基本上是一个名字，你必须使用
that same name on the other side of the
在另一边的那个名字
thing so you can see there's a the other
东西，所以你可以看到另一个
page that opens so when you visit this
打开的页面，因此当您访问此页面时
web sockets end page by just opening up
通过打开Web套接字结束页
a regular href in the new window
新窗口中的常规href
WebSockets and you can see here we've
WebSockets，您可以在这里看到
got an F event and it opens up which is
有一个F事件，它打开了
not a new thing F events been around
F事件不是新事物
since JSF - oh and the type is post
由于JSF-哦，类型是post
render view so in the JSF lifecycle
在JSF生命周期中呈现视图
after the view is rendered this event is
呈现视图后，此事件为
going to fire and it's going to call
将要开火，它会打电话
this WebSocket beam send method and
此WebSocket光束发送方法和
let's step into that so here this is
让我们进入其中，这是
just a plain old CDI beam and we are
只是一个普通的旧CDI光束，我们
injecting the push context and the name
注入推送上下文和名称
of the push context is my channel and we
推送上下文是我的频道，我们
are sending the alert so this my channel
正在发送警报，所以这是我的频道
thing matches up with the my channel
事情与我的频道相符
over here also the on message that's
在这里也是on消息
going to be evaluated so when the
将被评估，所以当
WebSocket beam sends this thing that's
WebSocket Beam发送的是
going to call over to this guy here
要打电话给这个家伙
function alert message and just take the
功能警报消息，然后采取
alert and
警报和
so and then we can go back up to the
因此，我们可以返回到
index so any questions on that yep
索引，以便对这个有任何疑问
right yes that's a different we have a
是的，这是不同的，我们有一个
different feature for that the question
该问题的不同特征
was this example is just communicating
这个例子只是交流
for one page to another the WebSocket
一个页面到另一个WebSocket
push is forwent is a one-way thing when
当被推挤是单向的事情
the server wants to send something down
服务器要发送一些消息
to the client so whether it's one pages
给客户，所以无论是一页
there's several different pages it's not
有几个不同的页面
going out anywhere else
到其他地方去
so the client calling back is the one
所以客户回电就是那个
I'll be talking about next that's the F
接下来我要说的是F
colon command script okay question there
冒号命令脚本好吗那里的问题
fill mmm question was do I know if the
填写mmm问题是我是否知道
autocomplete is working IntelliJ
自动完成工作IntelliJ
hairclips I don't know yeah I hope I
发夹我不知道是的，我希望我
mean usually they get it this is one of
意味着通常他们得到它，这是其中之一
those things where when Oracle decided
甲骨文决定的那些事
last year the big news the big donation
去年大新闻大捐款
news you kind of see a pattern here
新闻你有点在这里看到一个模式
a lot of divesting going on so when we
进行大量剥离，所以当我们
did that news we gave it to Apache and
那件事我们把它给了阿帕奇
you know that's still it's a big thing
你知道那仍然是一件大事
so that's still in process you got a
所以这仍在进行中
question
题
I believe it would go in all the
我相信它将在所有
question was if you had multiple copies
问题是您是否有多份副本
of the same page and you did to push
在同一页面上，您确实要推送
would it show and up in all of them I
它会出现在所有人身上吗？
think it would because it's the browser
认为这是因为它是浏览器
knows those connections in those
知道那些联系
channels any other questions you know
引导您知道的其他任何问题
ah I can try I don't have that zoom
啊，我可以尝试，我没有那个变焦
thing turned on I was messing with the
事情打开了，我在弄乱
resolution let me just try to do that
分辨率让我尝试做到这一点
over here this old-fashioned way
在这里过时的方式
yeah I don't know I've already got it
是的，我不知道我已经知道了
running at the lowest one uh you know
以最低的速度运行
how you want to come up Dave and help me
你想怎么来戴夫帮我
but I think I may have turned that off
但我想我可能已将其关闭
somehow
不知何故
yeah I know I somehow turn that off
是的，我知道我以某种方式将其关闭
that's okay yeah I was wrecked bad and
没关系，是的，我很糟糕，
it's yeah I know but I've got it turned
是的，我知道，但我知道了
off something on preferences sorry about
关掉一些关于偏好的东西
that huh I don't know it's it's not
那个我不知道是不是
going I'm sorry yeah I'll try I'll try
对不起，我会尝试的，我会尝试的
to speak it out more and you know you
多说出来，你知道你
you can check out the samples yourself
您可以自己检查样本
and see them so that's the best I can do
看到他们，这是我能做的最好的
at this point I'm sorry alright let's go
此时，对不起，我们走吧
back to the next one that I wanted to
回到我想要的下一个
mention over here
在这里提到
Ajax method of vocation so this one is
因此，Ajax的职业方法是
implemented using the command script tag
使用命令脚本标记实现
and it's very simple so let's take a
这很简单，让我们来
look at what he's doing in the code
看看他在代码中做什么
there command script an example of using
那里的命令脚本使用示例
server-side Ajax invocation with JSF yes
使用JSF进行服务器端Ajax调用是
so you can see there's no ABCD
这样就可以看到没有ABCD
hard-coded in the page we are simply
硬编码在页面中，我们只是
calling over to command script being
调用命令脚本
execute so this will cause an ajax
执行，这将导致一个ajax
request to be sent to the server and the
请求发送到服务器和
response will you know re render the
您是否会知道重新渲染
output section here so if you've used
输出部分在这里，如果您使用过
the F : Ajax tag this is very similar
F：这个Ajax标签非常相似
but this just allows you to rear-end
但这只允许您追尾
send the output directly back from this
直接从此发送输出
thing and have it go where you want to
东西，把它放到你想去的地方
do it there so let's look I think we're
在那里做，让我们看看我认为
just going to see right taking the input
只会看到正确的输入
lower case and upper case yet and
小写和大写都没有
sending it back so again really nice and
再寄回去真的很好
simple example and it's you have to set
简单的例子，这是你必须设置
it to auto run on true.you if you don't
它会在true.you上自动运行
set it to auto run then
然后将其设置为自动运行
well you could bind it to certain events
好吧，你可以将它绑定到某些事件
in the page and the name I think is
在页面上，我想的名字是
optional so any questions on from an
可选，因此来自
script this is another one was community
脚本这是另一个社区
contributed by the community okay all
由社区贡献好所有
right next up is multi field validation
接下来是多字段验证
this one is using F : validate whole
这是使用F：整个验证
beam and I'm gonna take a little chance
梁，我要抓住一点机会
again here and see if I can find where I
再次在这里，看看我能否找到我在哪里
put this
把这个
yeah
是的
okay
好的
okay alright so the let's go up to the
好吧，让我们开始吧
top level of the Javadoc I hope this is
我希望这是Javadoc的顶层
going to do it for me
要为我做
index.html JSF fake I know
index.html我知道的JSF伪造
okay yeah if you go now it's so that's
好的，是的，如果你现在就去，那就是
that's the Firefox soon yeah if you look
那就是Firefox很快，是的，如果您看
at the jsf Javadoc that's on the public
在公开的jsf Javadoc中
website which is github I'm sorry
对不起的是github的网站
Java EE that github that I Oh slash
我噢削减的github的Java EE
JavaServer faces spec there should be a
JavaServer面临规范，应该有一个
link to Java doc on here and if you go
链接到此处的Java文档，如果可以的话
and find that you'll come to this page
并发现您将来到此页面
as well same thing you'll see here and
同样，您会在这里看到和
it's got this color-coded thing so you
它有这个颜色编码的东西，所以你
can easily see which stuff has changed
可以轻松查看哪些内容已更改
and what's added and new so if we look
以及新增和新增的内容，因此，如果我们看一下
at the VTL doc if we go to f we should
在VTL文档中，如果我们转到f
see validate whole bean there we are so
看到验证整个豆在那里
this supports multi field validation by
这支持通过
enabling class of Lavina validation so
启用Lavina验证类别，因此
it's entirely based on CDI and let's
它完全基于CDI，让我们
look at the code
看代码
okay
好的
now they'd hold me here we are so we
现在他们会抱着我在这里，所以我们
have two text fields input text one with
有两个文本字段输入一个文本
value one and you can see it's got the
值一，你可以看到它具有
validate beam tag in it and then the
验证其中的光束标签，然后
other input text two with the validate
其他输入文本两个带有验证
beam inside it and then finally you have
里面的光束，最后你有了
this one at the bottom here who refers
这是底部的那个
to the whole beam so the key thing is
整个光束，所以关键是
regular JSF validation is based on
定期的JSF验证基于
fields whereas CDI validation is based
字段，而CDI验证基于
on objects pojos really and with CDI
真正地和CDI一起处理pojos对象
validation when we integrated it in JSF
当我们将其集成到JSF中时进行验证
2.0 we had them add a feature to CDI
2.0我们让他们为CDI添加了功能
which was if I was to hand you a model
那是如果我要给你一个模特
with this value in it would it be valid
带有这个值将是有效的
and it would return us this enabled
它将使我们返回启用状态
whether it was valid or not this enabled
是否有效
us to kind of preemptively do that check
我们先发制人地进行检查
whereas the real way CDI wants to
而CDI想要的真正方法
operate is preventing invalid stuff from
操作阻止了无效的东西
ever entering into the model so you
曾经进入模型，所以你
would give the object to the thing
将物体带给事物
actually no it's the other way it's like
其实不，那是另一种方式
you have the stuff injected in the model
您已经在模型中注入了东西
already and you would validate the whole
已经，您将验证整个
thing and would say if it was valid or
并会说这是否有效或
not so what we do here is sort of turn
不是，所以我们在这里要做的是转弯
it upside down and push the values into
倒置并将值推入
a beam and then ask CDI to do the
光束，然后要求CDI做
validation specifically during this part
专门在此部分进行验证
right here so if we look at the whole
就在这里，所以如果我们看整个
beam that we're passing in here he has
我们在这里经过的光束
to find a new annotation where is this
找到一个新的注释在哪里
yes he added a constraint so the
是的，他添加了一个约束，所以
constraint this is a standard this is
约束，这是一个标准，这是
how you do it you just find a constraint
你怎么做，你只是找到一个约束
validator and then it's got a POJO
验证器，然后有一个POJO
values here set value one and set value
此处的值设置为一和设置值
two and
两个和
just look at this code is validator
只是看这段代码是验证器
being no that's a different one okay
不，那是另一回事
trying to find the where the business
试图找到业务所在
logic is that's it the whole validator
逻辑就是整个验证器
it's actually gonna be just in this case
实际上是在这种情况下
showing false all the time so this is
一直显示错误，所以这是
where you would be able to take the
您将能够采取的
whole beam here and check the values so
整个光束在这里，并检查值，以便
let's let's make a change here let's do
让我们在这里进行更改让我们做
some live coding if we run it in the
一些实时编码，如果我们在
browser list of sample apps go up and go
示例应用程序的浏览器列表不断增加
back to validate whole beam whatever I
回到验证整个光束，无论我
put in here it's gonna give me invalid
放在这里会给我无效的
unable to validate mean so let's just
无法验证意味着，让我们只是
change this to true and redeploy the
将此更改为true并重新部署
application redeploying already and if
应用程序已经重新部署，如果
we do this I'm hoping it's gonna work
我们这样做我希望它能工作
yeah it worked it didn't complain you're
是的，它奏效了，没有抱怨你
not seeing the message there so what
没有在那里看到消息怎么办
you're actually passed here is the whole
你实际上是通过这里的整体
beam and you can inspect all of the
梁，您可以检查所有
properties that are set and then compare
设置然后比较的属性
them so the most common example that's
他们，所以最常见的例子是
used here is typing the password field
这里使用的是输入密码字段
twice right so you have to make sure the
两次正确，所以您必须确保
first value is the same as the second
第一个值与第二个相同
value so in order to do that you need a
价值，因此，要做到这一点，您需要
validator that is handed an object that
传递给对象的验证器
has all of the properties in it so it's
具有所有属性，因此
not just it could be any number of
不仅可以是任何数量的
fields that you can inspect on the beam
您可以在光束上检查的字段
so it's kind of flexible like that any
所以像任何一种
questions on that okay
问题就可以了
yeah that was literal there's a funny
是的，确实是一个有趣的
thing about the issue tracker this that
关于问题跟踪器的事情
was literally issue number one but when
实际上是第一号问题，但是当
we did JSF 1.0 1.2 we didn't have the
我们做了JSF 1.0 1.2我们没有
bean validation framework but we knew it
bean验证框架，但我们知道
was coming so this is one of those
来了，所以这是其中之一
people say oh Java EE is so slow well
人们说哦，Java EE太慢了
yes it is but if you're gonna take in
是的，但是如果你要接受
stuff from all over the place and do it
来自各地的东西，并做到这一点
right and have abstractions go to the
正确并具有抽象去
right layer you know that's the thing we
正确的层，你知道那是我们的事情
we have a huge enterprise thing here and
我们这里有一个庞大的企业，
sure we could define our own solution
确保我们可以定义自己的解决方案
invent our own api's and do it ourselves
发明自己的api并自己做
right that's not the right thing for the
对，那不是正确的事情
platform now that we have CDI and bean
平台，现在我们有了CDI和bean
validation you can use validation all
验证您可以全部使用验证
across the place not just for the for
遍地不只是为了
JSF and this is one of the things that
JSF，这是
the web framework Wars made JSF look so
Web框架Wars使JSF看起来如此
bad because they didn't have any of that
不好，因为他们没有任何
you can call it baggage but I actually
你可以称它为行李，但我实际上
call it doing it doing it right for the
称它为正确做
whole platform they can just innovate
他们可以创新的整个平台
and build stuff straight into their
并直接在他们的东西
specs and that specs rather their
规格，而不是它们的规格
implementations without having to worry
实施而不必担心
about other people taking advantage of
关于其他人利用
it so kind of a tragedy of the commons
这是公地的悲剧
type thing all right let's see tighter
好吧，让我们来看看
CDI integration now this one really was
CDI集成现在这真的是
kind of under the radar but took a fair
有点在雷达之下，但公平
amount of work and it doesn't demo so
大量的工作，并且没有演示
well because it's like okay yeah this is
好吧，因为这就像是，这是
how it should work to begin with but I
首先应该如何工作，但我
think Manfred did put some great
认为曼弗雷德确实做了一些伟大的事情
examples in here up CDI injection
CDI注入示例
samples yes he's got few of them okay ah
样本是的他很少可以啊
this is a good way to do it so a
这是一个很好的方法，所以
non-exhaustive list of injection target
非详尽的注射目标清单
so we one of the things we did was just
所以我们做的一件事就是
make a ton of stuff more injectable JSF
使大量的东西更具可注射性
has all of these objects like you know
有所有这些对象，就像你知道的
the knit parameter the header map
knit参数标题表
application map basis context you can
您可以基于应用程序映射基础上下文
just inject them in your
只需将它们注入您的
beans very easily so if we looked at
豆很容易，所以如果我们看着
this page I expect we're going to see a
我希望在此页面上看到一个
lot of al expressions and then they're
很多表达式，然后它们是
gonna be pointed to beans that are gonna
会被指向要去的豆子
show us all of those properties inject
向我们展示所有这些属性注入
okay right oh that I went I did index
好吧，哦，我去了，我做了索引
sorry yes indeed
对不起，确实是
so inject being injected artifacts so
所以注入被注入的假象
let's look at an inject mean right so
让我们看一下注入均值
you can see here these are all the
你可以在这里看到这些都是
things you can now inject and this this
现在可以注入的东西，这个
is such a great example because it just
就是一个很好的例子，因为它只是
shows everything in one place and it all
在一处展示所有内容
is just done with the regular CDI way
只是用常规的CDI方法完成
you expect it to do and it's putting
你期望它会做，它把
some values in here and using the post
此处和使用帖子中的一些值
construct annotation so let me ask the
构造注释，所以让我问
audience is anyone still using old
听众是谁还在用旧
fashioned regular JSF managed beans you
老式的常规JSF托管bean
are okay so does CDI seem like something
没关系，CDI看起来像什么吗
you would want to move to of course okay
你当然想搬到
anyone else want to share on that does
其他人想分享的是
this you want to get to CDI eventually
您最终想要获得CDI的
possibly okay
可能还可以
and doing Tomcat yeah right right okay
然后做Tomcat是的，好吧
so David is pointing out a very common
所以大卫指出了一个非常普遍的
usage pattern for JSF which I'd like to
我想要的JSF使用模式
pull the audience here for who is using
将观众吸引到谁在使用
JSF just on straight Tomcat with no
JSF仅在不带直线的Tomcat上
other Java EE stuff right okay so that
其他Java EE的东西还可以，这样
just comes from the you know the thing
只是来自你知道的东西
that's the kind of web framework thing I
我就是那种Web框架
was talking about earlier and this is
之前在谈论，这是
one of the things that Apache Tommy has
Apache Tommy拥有的一件事
really addressed quite well is it's this
真的很好解决是这样的
is why I think David Blevins has got a
这就是为什么我认为David Blevins有一个
really good opportunity to make some
真正的机会，使一些
great progress here
这里进步很大
it's Tomcat but it also has open web
它是Tomcat，但也有开放的网络
beans and c-d-i stuff baked in so it's a
豆和CDI东西烤出来的
good option for that anyhow the reason I
无论如何，我的好选择
point this out is there's a bit of a
指出这一点是有一点
learning curve with CVI and one of the
与CVI和其中之一的学习曲线
things you have to keep in mind is that
你要记住的是
when you get this thing phases context
当你得到这个东西的阶段上下文
it's not the actual real phases context
这不是实际的实际阶段环境
that you could just you know down cast
那你就可以知道自己下调了
it to whatever implementation class you
它到您的任何实现类
want to know you're gonna be getting a
想知道你会得到一个
proxy and they do everything in CDI with
代理，他们用
dynamic proxying so you have to accept
动态代理，因此您必须接受
that because the the magic secret sauce
那是因为神奇的秘密酱
with CDI is let's let CDI do all of the
让CDI让CDI做到所有
creating of things you don't ever use
创造您从未使用过的东西
operator new in an injection type
注射类型的新操作员
framework which is the same thing for
框架是相同的
spring spring does the proxy as well
春天春天也做代理
okay and let's see we have let's see we
好吧，让我们看看我们有，让我们看看我们
started at 45 right we started yeah five
从45开始，我们开始是5
minutes okay thanks well that's what I
分钟好，谢谢，这就是我的意思
wanted to know okay well those are all
想知道好吧，这些都是
the features I wanted to get through and
我想了解的功能和
I wanted to save questions so five to
我想保存问题，所以五个
ten minutes
10分钟
let me put up the sessions of interest
让我安排感兴趣的会议
slide current slide and while I take
滑动当前幻灯片，而我拍
questions these are some other ones in
这些是其他一些问题
particular I want to mention come on
我特别想提一提
give me over here the portland deep dive
给我在这里波特兰深潜
tonight at 5:30 my good friend Vernon
今晚5:30我的好朋友弗农
singleton so that one's great these
单身人士，所以这些很棒
these are all gonna be awesome sessions
这些都是很棒的会议
I'm gonna probably try to get to as many
我可能会尝试去尽可能多的人
of them I probably get to all try to
他们中，我可能会全力以赴
push with that so any other open
推开它，以便其他打开
questions here yes the the clips I think
这里的问题是我认为的剪辑
Jay in contrast to Jay s in contrast to
杰伊与杰伊的对比
servlet jsf is like the ideal candidate
servlet jsf就像是理想的候选人
for moving forward it's got the active
向前迈进了
community there are at least two parties
社区至少有两个政党
Liferay and Omni faces that have
Liferay和Omni的面孔
expressed interest in taking over and
表示有兴趣接管和
moving the spec forward so and there
不断推动规范发展
might even be more but for me picking
可能甚至更多，但对我来说
either of those two parties would be
这两方中的任何一方都是
great because they're already in the
很好，因为他们已经在
community they already know how to do
他们已经知道该怎么做的社区
the thing they've known them for a long
他们认识他们很久的事情
time and they have an economic interest
时间，他们有经济利益
in moving it forward to let's let's be
在前进，让我们成为
frank Oracle does things for the
坦率地说，Oracle为
economic benefit of its shareholders and
股东的经济利益
that's a perfectly fine thing for a
对于一个人来说，这绝对是一件好事
public company to do and you know
上市公司做，你知道
everyone should remember that but in
每个人都应该记住，
order for other stakeholders to do it
命令其他利益相关者去做
they have to have that as well in case
他们也必须这样
of omni faces you know PR wants to be
知道公关想成为的全能面孔
successful and do that with and they've
成功并做到这一点，他们已经
got the right business plan and staffing
制定了正确的商业计划和人员配置
for that and the same is for life right
为此，人生也一样
they have a business model that's in
他们有一种商业模式
part to large part actually enabled by
部分到大部分实际上由
JSF so they would like to do that too
JSF，所以他们也想这样做
so I think it's all very good news from
所以我认为这都是来自的好消息
that front so any other questions you
那边，还有其他问题吗
know
知道
well if what I said my other servo talk
好吧，如果我说我的其他伺服讲话
is that servlet is so foundational that
servlet是这么基础的
it's going to be a lot more hard to get
这将变得更加困难
all of the existing stakeholders to
所有现有的利益相关者
continue to play on the same way that
继续以相同的方式进行比赛
they did with JCP I think I don't know
他们与JCP合作，我想我不知道
but it's more of a organizational
但这更像是一个组织
challenge than a technological one
挑战胜于技术挑战
although it's a technological one as
虽然这是一个技术
well because there's no history of
好吧，因为没有历史
swapping in different servlet
在不同的servlet中交换
implementations different containers
实现不同的容器
it's just like kind of part of the OS
就像操作系统的一部分一样
really
真
whereas for JSF it's always been kind of
而对于JSF来说，
pluggable so and I have a great debt of
可插拔的，我负债累累
gratitude to Manfred Guyler and martin
感谢曼弗雷德·盖勒和马丁
marin chick and all of the guys from
marin小妞和所有来自
aryan that are the company that's behind
落后的公司aryan
my faces and you know I've known them
我的脸，你知道我认识他们
for many years and it's been a real
多年以来，这是一个真实的
pleasure working with them over the
很高兴与他们合作
years as well any other questions
年以及其他任何问题
uh-huh
嗯
good question if you're using JSF with
一个好问题，如果您正在使用JSF与
spring does it mean you can't upgrade to
春天是否意味着您不能升级到
2.3 I do think that we have cast our lot
2.3我确实认为我们已经付出了很多
in with CDI so I would think the answer
与CDI合作，我想答案
is probably yes we're kind of really
可能是的，我们真的
trying to promote the CDI platform this
试图推广CDI平台
is one of the things that I hope the MVC
是我希望MVC要做的事情之一
specification is able to address so that
规范能够解决，以便
they're kind of portable as well I don't
他们也很便携
know okay if I think Berger out of time
知道好吗，如果我认为Berger没有时间
so thank you very much and I really
非常感谢你，我真的
appreciate your coming to the session
感谢您参加会议
and I wish you all the best
祝你一切顺利
[Applause]
[掌声]